Criterion 2.4.7 Focus Visible.
Let's start by saying what its purpose is
its purpose is to make active elements more visible to users
then form and link fields.
Criterion 2.4.7 can be applied with various techniques
these in particular are the C15, the G195 and the G165.
The C15 technique is intended to highlight
form and link fields to facilitate insertion
data or highlight selected hyperlinks.
To be visualized better they must be highlighted with a bright color.
G195 technique also this technique has the purpose of facilitating data entry by the user.
And highlight a link on a dark background
this is done by highlighting the fields that are activated based on the user's selection.
The link must be highlighted with a bright color and a yellow bar.
G165 technique also this technique has the purpose of facilitating data entry
but specifically, where it is usually more difficult to distinguish the elements
then on a dark page
In fact the field will turn an intense yellow
at the edges
this must also work with the index tab.
C15 technique applied.
So when we click on the input field so that it is more visible
esso assumerà un colore di sfondo molto acceso
In this case green.
To make the choice more visible
The option will be highlighted.
The link itself when we go over the link
it will be highlighted with a lightblue color.
Now we will see the G195 technique applied.
When we click with the mouse to enter the data
the input will be underlined with a red color.
In the case of a dark page the link must become
yellow with a yellow border.
Adesso vedremo la tecnica G165 applicata.
So in a dark page
the input element when clicked must take a yellow outline
or in any case very bright
and the same thing must work with the index tab.
Now we will see programmatically how to apply the C15 technique.
Let's start with the checkbox.
If the input type is the same as the checkbox and is focus
and the input is the same as the button and is focus
then the option will be highlighted in a very bright color.
Now we see the highlighted input so if the input dot class is focus
then it is clicked assumes a different background color.
Now let's see the C15 technique for the highlighted link.
If element a is hover
then the user passes over it with the mouse.
Or if it is active, if it is focus it takes on a different background color.
How to apply the G195 technique programmatically.
Form elemnt.
As the criterion wants, it is placed inside a table
if the input point class is focus.
Then it assumes a bottom edge then below
of 5 red pixels.
For the link on a dark background if a dot class is hover
then it takes on a yellow color and double underline.
How to apply the G165 technique.
If the input dot class is focus then it assumes
a 4 pixel yellow border.